rypple.com 2012-09-17

# Privacy Policy | Rypple

Updated June 7, 2012

[](https://privacy.truste.com/privacy-seal/Salesforce-com,-Inc-/validation?TRUSTEDCLOUD%20rid=cfc7f80c-981b-4fd4-947b-6fd3c88a0e40 "Validate TRUSTe
privacy certification")

[](https://privacy.truste.com/privacy-seal/salesforce-com,-inc-/validation?rid=65fcf0dd-ce7d-4b90-b353-a83ed923117d "TRUSTe European
Safe Harbor certification")

This Privacy Statement describes Rypple’s Web site privacy practices. All capitalized terms used in this Privacy Statement are either defined herein or in the Rypple Terms of Service.

Rypple has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this Privacy Statement and related practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe’s [Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) and the [TRUSTed Cloud Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/trusted-cloud/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding this Privacy Statement or related practices, please contact us at [privacy@rypple.com](mailto:privacy@rypple.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through mobile devices.

Rypple complies with the US-EU Safe Harbor framework and the US-Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union and Switzerland respectively. Information regarding the both the US- EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks can be found at: <http://export.gov/safeharbor>.

## 1\. Web Sites Covered

This Privacy Statement covers the privacy practices of Rypple’s Web site, [http://www.rypple.com](http://www.rypple.com/). 

Rypple’s Web site may contain links to other Web sites. Rypple is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. Rypple encourages you to review the privacy statements of such Web sites to understand their privacy practices.

## 2\. Personal Information Collected

Rypple collects individually-identifiable information (“Personal Information”) from individuals who visit Rypple’s Web site (“Web Site Visitors”) and individuals who register to use the Rypple Services (“Customers”).

When expressing an interest in obtaining additional information about Rypple or registering to use the Rypple Services, Rypple requires you to provide contact information, such as first name, last name, email address, and phone number (“Required Contact Information”).

When purchasing the Rypple Services, Rypple requires you to provide financial qualification and billing information, such as billing name, billing address, and credit card number (“Billing Information”). Required Contact Information and Billing Information are referred to collectively as “Data About Rypple Customers.”

You can choose to log into the Rypple Services or comment on the Rypple blog using sign- in services, such as Google Connect or other providers. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to pre-populate our registration form with your respective Data About Rypple Customers. Services like Google Connect give you the option to share information about your activities on this Web site and others within your network via the Rypple Services.

As you navigate Rypple’s Web site, Rypple may collect information through the use of commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and Web beacons (“Web Site Navigational Information”). Web Site Navigational Information includes standard information from your Web browser (such as browser type and browser language), your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and the actions you take on the Rypple Web site (such as Web pages viewed and links clicked). For additional information about Rypple’s collection and use of Web Site Navigational Information, please click here. 

## 3\. Use of Personal Information Collected

Rypple uses Personal Information to perform the services requested.  For example, if you fill out a “Contact Me” Web form, Rypple will use the information provided to contact you about your interest in Rypple.

Rypple may also use Data About Rypple Customers for marketing purposes. For example, Rypple may use your respective Data About Rypple Customers to contact you to further discuss your interest in Rypple and to send you information regarding Rypple and our partners, such as information about promotions or events. Please view the Communications Preferences section of this Privacy Statement to control how your respective Data About Rypple Customers is used for marketing purposes.

Rypple uses Billing Information solely to check the financial qualifications and to collect payment for the Rypple Services.

Rypple uses Web Site Navigational Information to operate and improve Rypple’s Web site and the Rypple Services. Rypple may use Web Site Navigational Information alone or in combination with Data About Rypple Customers to provide personalized information about Rypple. For additional information about the use of Web Site Navigational Information, please click here.

## 4\. Sharing of Personal Information Collected

Rypple may share Data About Rypple Customers and Web Site Navigational Information with our service providers to perform the activities described in this Privacy Statement on Rypple’s behalf. Rypple may also share Data About Rypple Customers and Web Site Navigational Information with our service providers to ensure the quality of information provided. Unless otherwise described in this Privacy Statement, Rypple does not share, sell, rent, or trade Data About Rypple Customers or Web Site Navigational Information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

Rypple reserves the right to use or disclose Data About Rypple Customers or Web Site Navigational Information if required by law or if Rypple reasonably believes that use or disclosure is necessary to protect Rypple’s rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process.

## 5\. Web Site Navigational Information

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

Rypple’s Web site uses cookies to track Web site usage, to enable you to sign in to the Rypple Services, and to help personalize your online experience. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk through your Web browser via a Web server. It contains information about you that can later be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. Cookies allow Rypple to recognize you as a visitor or user when you return to our Web site or use the Services using the same computer and Web browser. Rypple uses cookies to store your preferences so that you do not have to repeatedly enter the same information, and to display your personalized content. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies or configure acceptance of cookies. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use all of the interactive features of the Rypple Web site or the Rypple Services that depend on cookies.

We, and our third party partners, use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie is set once you’ve logged in to the Rypple Services and remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. The next time you attempt to login to the Rypple Services, the persistent cookie allows us to recognize you as an existing user so that you do not need to log in to the Rypple Services again. If you log out of the Rypple Services, however, you will need to re-enter your password the next time you wish to access your account. A session cookie is used to enhance or customize a particular visit to the Rypple site. Session cookies expire after a short time or when you close your Web browser.

We employ, or our third party advertising partner employs, clear gifs (also known as Web beacons). Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier that, like cookies, track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, clear gifs are embedded on Web pages and are about the size of a pixel. We tie the information gathered by clear gifs to certain Data About Rypple Customers in order to assess the effectiveness of our content. In particular, we use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which email alerts have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our communications and marketing campaigns.

**Behavioral Advertising**

Rypple may also contract with third-party advertising networks that collect IP addresses and other Web Site Navigational Information on Rypple’s Web site, emails, and on third-party Web sites. Ad networks follow your online activities over time by collecting Web Site Navigational Information through automated means, including through the use of cookies. They use this information to provide advertisements about products and services tailored to your interests. You may see these advertisements on other Web sites. This process also helps us manage and track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. To learn more about these and other advertising networks and their opt-out instructions, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

**IP Addresses and URLs**

Due to Internet communications standards, when you visit or use Rypple’s Web site, we automatically receive the URL of the Web site from which you came and the Web site to which you go when you leave Rypple’s Web site. We also receive your computer’s Internet Protocol (IP) address (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), your computer operating system, the type of Web browser you are using, and your Internet Service Provider (ISP). This information is used to analyze overall trends to help us improve the Rypple Service.

**IP Addresses and URLs**

Rypple may collect aggregated data regarding use of the Rypple Services, including, without limitation, number of visitors to the Web site, frequency and patterns of use, tag usage, feedback request trends, etc. ("Aggregated Data"). Rypple uses Aggregated Data as a statistical measure and not in a manner that would identify you personally. Aggregated Data enables us to determine how often certain parts of Rypple’s Web site or the Rypple Services are used so that we can improve them. Rypple may make use of, or make such Aggregated Data available to, third parties, in any manner in our sole discretion.

## 6\. Public Forums, Refer a Friend, and Customer Testimonials

**Public Forums**

Rypple may provide bulletin boards, blogs, or chat rooms on Rypple’s Web site. Any information you choose to submit in such forums may be read, collected, or used by others who visit these forums, and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. Rypple is not responsible for the information you choose to submit to these forums.

To request removal of your information from such forums, contact us at [privacy@rypple.com](mailto:privacy@rypple.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. We may maintain copies of such information for our records.

**Refer a Friend**

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about the Rypple Web site or the Rypple Services, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend an email inviting him or her to visit the Rypple Web site, use the Rypple Services, or start a user account, as the case may be. Rypple stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this email and tracking the success of our referral program. For information about how you may invite others to join you in your use of the Rypple Services, please click here.

Rypple periodically posts corporate customer and user testimonials on our Web site, which may contain Personal Information such as the corporate customer’s or user's name. We obtain the customer's consent prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial.

## 7\. International Transfers of Personal Information

To facilitate Rypple’s global operations, Rypple may transfer and access Personal Information from around the world, including the United States. This Privacy Statement shall apply even if such information is transferred to other countries.

For European visitors to the Rypple Web site and Users of the Rypple Services, please note that in order to provide the information or services requested, your Personal Information may be transferred outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”). By visiting the Rypple Web site or using the Rypple Services, you agree to Rypple transferring your Personal Information outside the EEA.

## 8\. Communications Preferences and Access to Personal Information

Rypple offers Web Site Visitors and Customers who provide contact information a means to choose how Rypple uses the contact information provided. You may manage your receipt of marketing and non-transactional communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located at the bottom of Rypple’s marketing emails. Additionally, you may send a request specifying your communications preferences to [support@rypple.com](mailto:support@rypple.com). Users cannot opt out of receiving transactional emails related to their Rypple accounts.

Users of the Rypple Services may correct, update, or delete their respective Data About Rypple Customers by making changes on the “My Settings” page of the Rypple Services, by emailing Customer Support at [support@rypple.com](http://www.support@rypple.com/), or by directing their query to their corporate administrator (the corporate client of the Rypple Services). Rypple will respond to such requests within 30 business days.

will retain Data About Rypple Customers for as long as an account is active or as needed to provide the Rypple Services. Without limiting the foregoing, we will retain and use Customer’s Data About Rypple Customers as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## 9\. Data Submitted via the Rypple Services

**Customer Data**

Rypple’s customers may electronically submit data or information, including personal information, to the Rypple Services for hosting and processing purposes (“Customer Data”). In this capacity, Rypple acts as a processor or service provider and generally has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal information is processed via the Rypple Services. Rypple’s clients are solely responsible for providing notice to individuals concerning the purpose for which their personal information is collected.

In accordance with the [Rypple Terms of Service](http://www.rypple.com/legal), Rypple shall maintain appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards for protection of the security, confidentiality and integrity of Customer Data. Further, Rypple shall not (a) modify Customer Data, (b) disclose Customer Data except as compelled by law in accordance with the Rypple Terms of Service or as expressly permitted in writing by the relevant Rypple customer, (c) access Customer Data except to provide the Rypple Services and prevent or address service or technical problems, or at a relevant Rypple customer’s request in connection with a customer support matter.

**Inviting Others to Use Rypple via the Rypple Services**

To invite others at your organization to join your instance of the Rypple Services, you may enter the other individual’s email address. This information will be used by Rypple to send your invitation including a message that you would like to work with the other person in the Rypple Services. The email addresses of individuals you invite will be used to send your invitation and reminders. If such individuals register to use the Rypple Services, their information will be treated as Data About Rypple Customers in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

## 10\. Security

Rypple takes precautions, including administrative, technical, and physical measures – to help safeguard Data About Rypple Customers against loss, theft, and misuse as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

Rypple uses Secure Socket Layer (“SSL”) encryption when transmitting sensitive Personal Information, such as credit card information and Users’ passwords.

Users are solely responsible for protecting their passwords, limiting access to their computers, and signing out of the Rypple Services after their sessions.

## 11\. Feedback Requests via the Rypple Services

Customers may solicit feedback from others, including non-Users, via the Rypple Services. Such feedback may be provided anonymously. If someone is not a User and is responding to a request for feedback from a User, then the respondent will not be asked to register.

## 12\. Changes to this Privacy Statement

Rypple reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement. Rypple will provide prior notification of material changes to this Privacy Statement through the Rypple Web site. If you continue to access the Rypple Web site or use the Rypple Services after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on the Rypple Web site, you will be deemed to have provided your consent to the changed practices.

## 13\. Changes to this Privacy Statement

Questions regarding this Privacy Statement or the information practices of Rypple should be directed to Rypple Privacy at [privacy@rypple.com](mailto:privacy@rypple.com) or Rypple Privacy (c/o salesforce.com), The Landmark @ One Market Street, San Francisco, CA 94105.
